[
  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of useEffect() in React?",
    "options": [
      "To trigger a function whenever the component is re-rendered",
      "To handle side effects like data fetching, DOM manipulation",
      "To trigger a function whenever the component loaded at first",
      "To trigger a function whenever the component specific state changes",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will cause useEffect() to run every time the component is rendered?",
    "options": [
      "useEffect(() => { ... }, [])",
      "useEffect(() => { ... }, [dependency])",
      "useEffect(() => { ... })",
      "return () => { ... }"
    ],
    "answer": "useEffect(() => { ... })"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will cause useEffect() to run whenever the component loaded at first?",
    "options": [
      "useEffect(() => { ... }, [])",
      "useEffect(() => { ... }, [dependency])",
      "useEffect(() => { ... })",
      "return () => { ... }"
    ],
    "answer": "useEffect(() => { ... }, [])"
  },
  {
    "question": "You want useEffect() to run every time ANY state changes. Which option does that?",
    "options": [
      "useEffect(() => { ... }, [])",
      "useEffect(() => { ... }, [dependency])",
      "useEffect(() => { ... })",
      "return () => { ... }"
    ],
    "answer": "useEffect(() => { ... })"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will cause useEffect() to run whenever the component unmount?",
    "options": [
      "useEffect(() => { ... }, [])",
      "useEffect(() => { ... }, [dependency])",
      "useEffect(() => { ... })",
      "return () => { ... }"
    ],
    "answer": "return () => { ... }"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the return value of useEffect() in React?",
    "options": [
      "A promise",
      "A cleanup function",
      "The current state value",
      "The components previous render state"
    ],
    "answer": "A cleanup function"
  },
  {
    "question": "You set an interval inside useEffect() but forget to clean it up. What happens in a real app?",
    "options": [
      "Multiple intervals keep running after component unmount.",
      "The app becomes slow over time",
      "Memory leaks may happen",
      "React will not automatically clean up.",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of setInterval()?",
    "options": [
      "It executes a function once after a delay",
      "It executes a function repeatedly at specified time intervals",
      "It stops a running timer",
      "It cleans up subscriptions"
    ],
    "answer": "It executes a function repeatedly at specified time intervals"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of clearInterval()?",
    "options": [
      "It starts a timer",
      "It executes a function repeatedly",
      "It stops a timer started by setInterval()",
      "It updates state automatically"
    ],
    "answer": "It stops a timer started by setInterval()"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do you correctly start and stop a timer in a React component?",
    "options": [
      "clearInterval(stop)",
      "clearInterval(timer)",
      "timer.stop()",
      "useEffect.stop(timer)"
    ],
    "answer": "clearInterval(timer)"
  },

  {
    "question": "If a parent component re-renders 10 times, how many times will a child component re-render?",
    "options": ["1 time, always", "10 times, unless optimized", "0 times", "5 times"],
    "answer": "10 times, unless optimized"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parent component passed props to a child component, how to stop unnecessary re-renders of child?",
    "options": [
      "By using useCallback() on the function in the parent component",
      "By using useEffect() in the child component",
      "By using React.memo() in the child component",
      "By setting the props with default value"
    ],
    "answer": "By using React.memo() in the child component"
  },
  {
    "question": "What types of data can be passed as props in React?",
    "options": [
      "A primitive data can be passed as props",
      "A function can be passed as props",
      "Object data can be passed as props",
      "Array data can be passed as props",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a callback function?",
    "options": [
      "A function that automatically runs when the component mounts.",
      "A function passed as a prop, and its execution is decided by the child",
      "A function that returns another function",
      "A function passed to child as props"
    ],
    "answer": "A function passed as a prop, and its execution is decided by the child"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is TRUE about useCallback()?",
    "options": [
      "It re-create the function when the component is re-render",
      "It should not re-create the function every re-render",
      "It is stop the child component re-render.",
      "The child is re-render only when the props changes."
    ],
    "answer": "It should not re-create the function every re-render"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a two-way data binding scenario (parent ↔ child), what is typically passed to the child?",
    "options": [
      "A copy of the parent’s state.",
      "A callback function to update the parent state.",
      "A useCallBack() function.",
      "A React.memo() function."
    ],
    "answer": "A callback function to update the parent state."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true about React.memo()?",
    "options": [
      "It re-create the function when the component is re-render",
      "When the parent is re-render child re-render",
      "It is stop the child component re-render",
      "It is stop the parent component re-render"
    ],
    "answer": "It is stop the child component re-render"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parent wants to update its state when child interacts. What must be passed?",
    "options": ["State only", "UseCallback() function", "Callback function", "Props drilling"],
    "answer": "Callback function"
  },
  {
    "question": "React.memo() will stop child re-render, But when the child is re-render?",
    "options": [
      "when the parent re-render",
      "when the props changes",
      "when the parent state changes",
      "When the function not re-created"
    ],
    "answer": "when the props changes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not true about React Component Communication?",
    "options": [
      "By default One-way communication parent → child",
      "Two-way communication is enable using React.memo()",
      "Two-way communication is enable using callback functions.",
      "The React component will communication using props."
    ],
    "answer": "Two-way communication is enable using React.memo()"
  }
]
